Both HDFCO Optima Secure and Aitya Birla
Activ 1 Max are very comprehensive
plans.  And if you are confused about
which of the two plans would be
more suitable for you, then
after watching this video all your doubts will be cleared.
In this video I have done a
detailed comparison of both the plans.  Based on their
features, benefits, claim matrix and
premium.  So, do not skip this video at all.
Watch the video till the end.  Hello friends, I am
Ashutosh.  Your personal finance coach.  Let's
start the video.  HDFC Aego
Optima Secure is a very popular plan and has been
recommended by many advisors for a long time.  At the same time,
Aitya Birla Capital's health
insurance plan Activ Max has
come into limelight in the recent times and many
good advisors have also started recommending it.
So let's see.  Talking about the minimum and
maximum entry age,
in both the plans the minimum entry age is 18 years
and the maximum is no entry age.
You can enter at any age.
As usual, it is 90 days for a dependent child.
Newborn babies are covered only after 90 days.
Sum Assured option
is 5 lakh to 2CR in Optima Secure.  Whereas Active One
Max has options of Rs 5 lakh to 2 CR.
Same in both.
NA rooms are available in room category Optima Secure.  There is no
room category wise capping in Active One Max also.
Which is a very good feature.  The
cost of treatment covered under our health insurance is associated with the room.
Therefore, we should take such policies in
which there is no room wise capping.
AYUSH Treatment Ayurvedic, Unani
Siddha, Homeopathy, these alternate
treatments
are covered up to sum assured in both the plans in both the variants.
Pre & Post Hospitalization Optima
Secure is covered for 60 days and 180 days.
Active One Max has cover for 90 days and
180 days.  Day care treatments are
covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  All Day Care Treatment.  What are day care
treatments?  Normal health
insurance covers hospitalization beyond 24 hours.
But there are some
treatments which require
hospitalization.  But
their complete procedure is completed in just a few hours of treatment.
He
comes for day treatment.  Organ donor cover
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  Organ donor cover.  Domiciliary
hospitalization is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.
Domiciliary
hospitalization is such hospitalization
when we take hospitalization at home.
If there is no bed in the nearby hospital
or the patient's condition is so critical
that we cannot take him to the hospital.  And at
such times, when we take hospitalization at home,
it
comes under domestic hospitalization.  Home care treatment is
available in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure and
also in Active One.  Up to sum assured
covers both variants.  It
is a very good benefit.  Road Ambulance
is covered up to some ash in both variants.  There
is no capping.  Air ambulance
is available at Optima Secure.  Not available in Active Max.
Free health checkup
is available in both the plans.  Inbuilt modern treatment
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  There is no capping.  Second
Medical Opinion is available once per person at Optima Secure.
Edge is an add-on available in the Active One Max.  E-consultation
is inbuilt.  And Active One is a
health management program at Max.  He is a type of
rider.  This e-consultation is a part of it.
Maternity cover is available only for parenthood.
Aditya is
not in Bel 1 Max in HDFC and Optimal Secure.  However, this
maternity cover is quite expensive.  Newborn
baby cover is a part of maternity cover.
But it is not there in both the variants.
HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure has the option for worldwide cover.  We can take
two variants Optima Secure Global and Global Plus.
Global
covers us emergency hospitalization.
Global cover is not available in Active One Max for End Global Plus Plant Hospitalization.  The
plan variants are Optima Secure,
Optima Super Secure Global and Global
Plus which are for global cover.
In Optima Super Secure, when we pay three years premium
together, we get 3x coverage
together.  1x which is our policy
and 2x extra cover is available.
In Optima Secure we get 1x extra cover.
Apart from Active One Max, Active One comes in Next and Vital variants.
Next is its online version which is
similar to HDFCO Optima Secure.
In Active One Next also we get 2X benefit
from day one just like in Optima Secure
we get 2X coverage.  Meaning if the
policy is of Rs 10 lakh then it will cover Rs 20 lakh.   See you
in the next one.  But this next
variant is available only online.
Not available in agency model.
In the agency model, you get the Max variant.  And it
comes with a Vital variant.  If the
policy holder has a more critical condition,
then he takes Vital instead of Max.
Waiting Periods All plants have an
initial waiting period of 30 days.
Apart from that, there is a two-year specific waiting
period for slow-growing diseases
which are covered after two years.  For example, a
three-year waiting period will be applicable for hernia, prostate, cataract and pre-existing conditions.
Talking about the unique benefits of these plans,
in HDFCO Optimus Secure we get Secure Benefit in
which we get 1X extra
coverage.  Meaning, if
you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then there is an additional coverage of Rs 10 lakh.
So this way it gives 2X coverage
from day one.  And if you take the Super Secure variant, it
gives 3X coverage from day one.  Meaning you
get 2x extra coverage.  For the Super Secure
variant, we have to pay the premium for 3 years
together.  Apart from that, plus
benefits are also available.  Meaning this
is a cumulative bonus.  Bonus is available twice at 50-50%
maximum up to 100%.  So, we get 2x coverage
from day one, 1x coverage from bonus
and 1x coverage
from restoration.  In such HDFC and Optima Secure, the
company tells us about 4X benefit.  The
restoration benefit is optional but
we get it at a very low premium
for all related and unrelated illnesses.
Apart from that, no
separate rider is required for non-payable non-medical items.
This protection benefit is inbuilt
which covers.  Apart from that, there is a
limitless option in which we
can claim once in a policy lifetime for policies less than Rs 50 lakh and twice in a policy lifetime unlimited amount for policies above Rs 50 lakh.
So, for example, if you have a policy of Rs 10-20 lakh and
you have a bonus of Rs 20-30 lakh, but if a claim
of Rs 1 crore comes,
this happens in many transplant cases.  So, through this option
you can exercise it.
Apart from that, lifestyle diseases like asthma,
blood pressure, cholesterol and diabetes.
This disease is quite common.  And
for these, usually we have to serve a waiting period of three years.  The
PED waiting
period is waived off through this rider.
Talking about Aditi Birla Active Max, the first one is
mental illness.  So both HIV and
mental illness are
not covered in health insurance.
Active One has it covered.  If these patients are
undergoing treatment then they cover it.
HIV is also covered.  Apart from that,
Super Reload in which we
get the benefit of unlimited time restoration.  There
are second claims.  Super Credit means we
get a bonus of 100%.  Up to 500% means up to 5x
our policy goes away.  100%
bonus is available every year.  Reduction in PD waiting
period.  So there is a
three year waiting period for normal pre-existing conditions.
But with this rider we
can reduce them for 2 years and one year also.
Another option we get is reduction in
specific disease waiting period.  So
for specific diseases we have a
waiting period of two years.  But with this rider
we can reduce that too.  Apart from that, the
biggest USP of this plan is
chronic care.  Friends, pre-existing
conditions like diabetes, hypertension,
asthma, hyperlipidemia, COPD,
obesity, coronary artery disease, if
you have had stunting before one year, then all these
things are covered very smoothly in this plan.  There are
many plans that
cover these conditions.  But this plan
covers it quite smoothly.  And specifically,
if you are not able to find a policy anywhere else
or have a pre-existing condition, which is at a chronic
level, then also you
can try with Aditya Billa.  A lot of underwriting is
their leaning.  Apart from this, there is a claim
protect which covers non-payable items.
Talking about optional benefits,
we get an NRI discount in Optima Secure.  There
is unlimited restoration.  There is a critical illness.  This is a lump sum
benefit.  Apart from that, hospital
cash, personal accident cover.  I always
advise that
we should take separate policies for critical illness and personal accident.
Not with health insurance.  Apart from that, there are
options of Optima Well Being and Deductible for OPD.  So
if the premium of the policy is getting high
then by taking a deductible of Rs. 25,000 or Rs. 50,000 we
can get a huge discount in our policy.
Reduction in specific disease waiting
period for Aditi Birla Activ Max riders.  Apart from that there is room rent option.  So there
is no inbuilt capping on room rent.
But if we want, we can put a capping on
single private room or shared room in our policy,
through which we will get some discount.
So we can consider a single private AC room
but
we should not take a room of a category below that.  PPN
Discount So Preferred Partner Network.
So all health insurance companies have some
preferred hospitals where they want
you to get treatment.  So
if you take this PPN rider then
you get some discount in the policy.
But in this you have to get your treatment done
in those hospitals only.
If you go outside to preferred hospitals,
you will have to pay.  As I mentioned, we should take critical illness
and personal accident cover
separately.  This
chronic care covers pre-existing conditions.
Chronic Management
Programme This is an OPD cover.  If you have
selected chronic care, then
you will be put into the chronic management program.  There is a
cancer booster which gives
you the benefit of additional sum assured in case of cancer.
Durable Medical Equipment.  If
you need any durable
medical equipment like wheelchairs and other
supporting equipment after hospitalization,
you can use it for renting or purchasing.
Compassionate Visit Second
Medical Opinion Annual Screening Package.
So, health checkup is free but
in the annual screening package, you get separate additional
packages for diagnosis of
cancer patients.  Talking about zone wise
premium, HDFC has two
zones.  There are three zones for the Aditya Birla Active One Max.
Talking about premium,
I have taken the example of a 35 year old couple
with two kids
in Zone One in Delhi NCR.  The
premium for HDFCO Optimal Secure is ₹30,000.  The
premium for F Active One Max is Rs 19,000.
So there is a lot of difference in the premium.
In both the plans we can take a policy for maximum 3 years.  If you
take a multi-year policy, you
get a discount.  Talking about claim experience, the
incurred claim ratio will be with HDFCR.
Is 84.25%.  Aditya Birla holds 71.50%.
So, the incurred claim ratio tells us
how well an insurance company is
paying claims.  84% means that it is
taking a premium of ₹100 and paying 84% in claims.  The
incurred claim ratio of Aditya Birla is 71%.  It means
average.  Not too much and not too little.
So we
can consider them as an average company.  Aditya Birla has made a lot of improvements in the last few years.
And many legacy companies
like nivpa kar star are much better than them.  The
claim settlement ratio is 93.51% and
9403%.
Talking about complaint ratio,
HDFC R has
15 in Optima Secure and 16 in Aditya Birla per 10,000 claims.
So the complaint ratio is also reasonable
in both the plans.  Talking about value for money,
HDFCR is considered optimal and
obviously on the expensive side.
Their premium is also a little higher.
Whereas Aditya Birla Active One Max
is fair valued.  If you are looking for a health
insurance plan in which you do
not have much problem with the premium.  You
can pay higher premium and fit and
find.  If there are not many pre-existing conditions
then HDFCO Optima Secure can be a
better option for you.  But if you have any
pre-existing conditions or are looking for
a good plan in a normal premium range, then
Adi Bella Active One can also be a
choice.  If you have a good
advisor who can give you good after sales service.  Can
help with your claims.
After sales
service plays a very important role in health insurance.
So try to take a policy from a good advisor.  If you want to
purchase a policy with me
or discuss health insurance
, discuss your investments, do
your financial planning, then you can connect
with me by visiting my website Ashtoshukl.com.  You
can book a paid consultation or connect with me through my WhatsApp number.  If you
liked the video, please like it.
Subscribe to the channel to watch more such informative videos.  That's all for
today's video.  See you
in the next video.  Thank you.